Kaiju No. 8...
怪獸8號…
He felt... strangely human.
牠散發出一股像人類的不尋常感
And then there's No. 9, which could speak and disguise itself as a human.
再加上會說人話，又能變成人類的9號
What's happening to the Kaiju?
這些怪獸到底是怎麼了？
Vice-Captain!
副隊長
I'll do my best to be able to help in the fight.
我會努力讓自己發揮戰力的
You can have 1% of my expectations.
我對你抱有1%的期待
I can't let him down!
我得回應他的期待
Okay, I've finally taken the first step!
好，我終於邁出第一步了
Time to get some sleep so I can be ready for tomorrow.
回去睡一覺，為明天作準備吧
Getting rest is part of the job, too...
休息也是工作的一部分
EPISODE 9: RAID ON TACHIKAWA BASE
（第9集：襲擊立川基地）
Operation room, what's going on?
作戰室，發生什麼事了？
We're seeing dozens of Kaiju inside the base!
基地內出現數十隻怪獸！
It appears the Kaiju have attacked us from the air!
根據現況判斷 怪獸有可能是由上空襲擊的
Estimated fortitudes 6.1, 6.3, 6.2, 6.5...
推測怪獸規模6.1、6.3、6.2、6.5…
Each and every one of them is...
所有個體…
K-Kaiju!
怪獸？
...Honju class?!
…都是主獸等級？
This is Hoshina.
我是保科
Captain Ashiro is away, so I'll be giving the orders here.
亞白隊長不在，所以由我代為指揮
Anybody who's on night watch, take battle stations.
夜間警備隊全員進入戰鬥狀態
Get the off-duty officers here, too.
並通知非值勤隊員緊急出動
All hands, prepare for combat.
-各自作好戰鬥準備 -瞭解
Lure as many as you can into the training area!
盡可能把怪獸引導至演習場
Make damn sure none of them get off the base!
絕對別讓牠們跑出基地
But we're not hearing any reports of damage from outside the base...
不過，目前還沒收到外部的受災報告
That can't mean...
難道…
Are they after the base itself?
這些傢伙的目標是這個基地？
What's going on?
這是怎麼回事？
The base...
基地…
is on fire!
陷入一片火海了
Wyvern-type Kaiju?
翼龍系怪獸？
Those things are bad news...
竟然出現這麼棘手的種類
Wyvern-types?
翼龍系？
But then... that means something's not right.
這樣的話，這些傢伙太奇怪了啊
Get anybody who uses a rifle together at the base's center.
擅長狙擊的隊員聚集到中央
-We'll lure them in and shoot them down. -Roger!
-把怪獸引過來後予以擊落 -瞭解
Vice-Captain!
副隊長！
Kafka! You're still alive, huh?
卡夫卡，你沒事啊？
Yes.
是的
But there's something wrong here.
不過，有一件事讓我很在意
Tell me.
說吧
You only see about a dozen or so wyvern-type Kaiju each year,
翼龍系怪獸每年大概會出現十隻左右
but there's always something they have in common.
牠們全都有個相同的特徵
They're always alone.
那就是牠們都單獨行動
But these guys showed up in a group!
但這些傢伙卻成群出現
Yeah. Which can only mean one thing...
嗯，這樣就只能想到一個原因
There's something out there with the power to make them swallow their pride,
有一個力量強大到可以管束 難以駕馭的翼龍系怪獸
and the intelligence to act with a goal in mind.
並能根據目標行動，具有智慧的
An incredibly powerful leader.
超強大的領導者
Target sighted.
發現目標
I'm hangin' up, Kafka.
我先掛斷了，卡夫卡
Are you the strongest human at this base?
這個基地裡最強的人是你嗎？
It can speak, too?
這傢伙也會說人話？
The captain ain't here,
隊長不在這裡
so yeah, I guess.
所以，就算是我了吧
I see.
這樣啊
That settles it, then. You are my prey.
那就決定把你當成我的獵物了
Honju's estimated fortitude calculations complete!
主獸的推測怪獸規模出來了
It's 8.3... That's Daikaiju class!
8.3？屬於大怪獸等級！
Ikaruga, do you copy?
-斑鳩，你聽得見嗎？ -是
You command the fight against the Yoju.
你負責指揮對付餘獸
Prioritize keeping them in the base and away from civilians,
首要任務是防止民間受害擴大
and keeping the main building online.
以及維持辦公廳舍的運作
Roger!
瞭解
As for the Honju, I'm...
主獸就由我…
You dodged it?
躲過了啊？
You pass.
你及格了
I'm gonna have to be the one to handle it.
這傢伙必須由我來對付
Excellent.
很好
Now... it's time.
那麼，現在正式開始
Let's begin your annihilation.
實施殲滅行動
The Yoju are reacting to its cry...
餘獸對此有所反應
So they are after this place.
牠們的目標果然是這裡
This thing's punches hit like a meteor strike!
彷彿隕石般的強大威力
One solid hit, and I'm a dead man.
要是被擊中一拳就完了
And its skin is tougher than No. 8's!
牠的皮膚比8號還硬啊
Fire!
開火！
It's unharmed?
竟然毫髮無傷？
Retreat!
撤退！
Gunners, swap to oscillator rounds.
狙擊手將彈藥換成重震動彈
Don't attack from the front!
正面攻擊沒用的
That voice... Hibino?
這聲音是日比野嗎？
You need to attack their backs.
要瞄準背部
They're the same type that was reported in '03!
牠們與03年記載的怪獸是同一種
Senpai?
前輩？
The old dude?
是大叔嗎？
I was worried when I couldn't get a hold of you!
一直聯絡不到你，我很擔心耶
Sorry, I was talking to the vice-captain.
抱歉，我剛在跟副隊長對話
Just hit the back, got it? The back!
總之攻擊背部就對了，瞄準背部！
The front is easier to hit when they're in flight,
牠們飛行時，正面較容易瞄準
but the skin's thick!
但那邊的皮膚很堅硬
The core should be near the back!
牠們的核心應該位於背部
The skin on the back is as thin as possible
而背部為了減輕體重
to help keep their weight down!
所以只有最低限度的硬度
Nice, Hibino!
做得好，日比野
Split up to run decoy in front while hitting the back!
兵分二路從正面分散怪獸的注意 另一人從背面攻擊
Roger!
瞭解
Get back.
你去後面
I'll take the front.
前面交給我來
I'll be the decoy.
我去當誘餌
Get behind it, Haruichi.
你繞去後面，陽一
You owe me one for this!
你欠我一次
He's good.
真有一套啊
Combat power, maximum release!
戰力全解放！
What?
什麼？
The Kaiju are working together?
怪獸竟然會攜手合作？
It's no good! We can't get behind them!
不行，我們無法從背後攻擊
We've failed as well!
我們也失敗了
Another Kaiju blocked us!
-遭到其他怪獸妨礙 -怎麼會？
What do we do?
怎麼辦？
If we can't get behind them, then how...
如果無法繞到背後，要怎麼攻擊？
There's another way.
還有一個方法
Shinomiya?
四之宮？
What do you mean, another way?
什麼方法啊？
I just...
就用我這身…
use my unstoppable power...
所向披靡的威力
to smash right through their front armor!
就從正面打爆牠們吧
TACHIKAWA BASE UNDERGROUND WEAPONS STORAGE ROOM
（立川基地，地下，武器保管室）
A custom weapon? For me?
我的專用武器？
I thought you had to be a captain to get one.
這不是隊長等級才會有的裝備嗎？
Normally, yeah.
通常是這樣沒錯
But we've decided it's worth making an exception.
但這是考量現況後作出的判斷
The fortitude levels and numbers of Kaiju we're seeing this year are abnormal.
今年怪獸的強度和數量皆異於往常
And, since you're the third most powerful officer on base,
而你的戰鬥力在基地中名列第三
we've decided to treat you as part of our main force.
因此我們決定讓你成為主力之一
Shinomiya, from now on,
四之宮，接下來
you're our third strongest weapon after the captain and vice-captain.
你將成為隊長和副隊長之後的第三戰力
It will be your job to annihilate the Kaiju.
負責殲滅怪獸
Hits pretty hard, for a prototype.
以原型品來說，威力還不錯
One thing I don't like, though,
如果要挑毛病的話
is that such an ugly weapon doesn't suit me.
就是這武器太粗獷，跟我不太搭了
S-She smashed through its front armor?
竟然從正面擊倒怪獸了
All right, you Kaiju...
好了，你們這些怪獸
Now that I'm on the battlefield,
有我在的戰場
it's over for you.
我才不會讓你們胡作非為呢
The weapon is primarily made from
這個武器的主要材料
the uniorgan of the Honju that was neutralized in Shinagawa two years ago.
是前年在品川討伐的主獸的單器官
Pull the trigger to turn on the power, and it'll release shock waves.
扣下扳機通電後，就會發出衝擊波
Usage one...
應用方法一
Generating a shock wave behind you when taking an action.
行動時向後方發出衝擊波
Accelerate!
加速！
Squadron-Style Ax Technique Number One: Falling Thunder!
隊式斧術1式，落雷
Usage two...
應用方法二
Unleashing a frontal shock wave on impact...
應戰時向前方發出衝擊波
for more power!
增加攻擊力
Number Two: Water Skimmer!
斧術2式，水切
Wow...
好厲害
What do you mean, it doesn't suit you?
這個武器哪裡跟你不搭了啊？
It's perfect for your aggressive, overbearing personality.
這跟生性好戰又高傲的你 簡直就是天生一對
Now, who's next?
那麼，接下來…
Above me?
在上面？
Freeze rounds?!
凍結彈？
Reno...
雷諾
Be careful, Shinomiya. They attack from the sky, too.
別掉以輕心，四之宮 牠們也會從上方發動攻擊
You aren't going anywhere!
我才不會讓你飛起來
I'm impressed he can fight like that against Kaiju this strong.
他竟然有辦法應付這種等級的怪獸
Number Three: Half Moon!
斧術3式，半月
Did she get them?
成功了
Reno.
雷諾
You can have the honor of helping me.
我就讓你來掩護我吧
If you can keep up, that is.
前提是你要跟得上我
Sounds great to me.
我奉陪到底
All right, search the battlefield for openings and catch the enemy off guard!
好，我們以游擊戰的方式擾亂敵軍
You heard that, right?
你聽見了吧？
Yeah.
嗯
A guerrilla squad of just two...
才兩個人就想擾亂敵軍
That sounds like Shinomiya.
真符合四之宮的作風
We can't let the two of them leave us behind.
我們不能被拋在腦後
Which means we need to...
既然這樣，我們就…
Hit the enemy from behind when Shinomiya's got 'em distracted!
繞到被四之宮引誘的怪獸後面攻擊
Shinomiya's team will stop the Kaiju from working together!
四之宮分隊會擾亂怪獸之間的合作
Continue the mission!
繼續進行作戰
Split into two and hit the enemy from behind!
兵分二路從背後攻擊怪獸
Shinomiya seems like she's doing her job just fine.
看來四之宮有發揮作用
The problem is...
問題在於…
This thing.
這傢伙
I-It's strong...
好強大…
But that's not all.
不僅如此
It's...
這傢伙…
enjoying the fight.
還很樂在其中
Okonogi-chan, open Gate 3!
小此木，開啟3號閘門
Roger!
瞭解
It's an emotion Kaiju aren't supposed to have.
這很明顯不是怪獸會有的情緒
Why'd I even bother opening it?
這樣開門還有什麼意義啊？
Those doors are expensive, okay?
那扇門很貴耶
Where'd it go?
牠去哪了？
Even most Kaiju can't fight me like you do.
能跟我對打這麼久的對象 就算是怪獸也找不到幾個呢
I can't wait to eat you and get even stronger.
我等不及想把你當作糧食吞下了
Vice-Captain!
副隊長！
You really are strong.
你真的很能打呢
Sorry, Okonogi-chan.
抱歉，小此木
This is an emergency, so I'm skipping the procedures.
由於事出緊急，我省略了申請程序
Here in the training grounds,
在這個演習場裡
I don't have to worry about hurting the officers if I go all out.
就算使出全力，也不必擔心會波及隊員
Unleashed combat power, 92%!
解放戰力，92%
All right, time to neutralize this Kaiju.
那就開始討伐怪獸吧
They're so powerful!
好強大的威力
I won't make it in time...
來不及了
If I just transform part of my body...
不對，如果我變身一部分…
H-Hibino-san?
日比野？
You okay, Minase?
水無瀨，你沒受傷吧？
Thanks!
謝謝你
I guess you learned to use your suit, huh?
你學會使用戰鬥服了啊
W-Well, I am a full officer, you know! So of course...
畢竟我也是正式隊員，這種程度…
Hibino-san, behind you!
日比野，你後面！
Kikoru!
琪歌露
You okay, Senpai?
你沒事吧？前輩
Reno and I will distract the Kaiju.
我和雷諾負責引開怪獸
Get the wounded out of here while we do.
麻煩你們趁現在去保護傷者
Roger!
瞭解
Senpai...
前輩
Just don't take any risks, please.
拜託你千萬別亂來
You're a full officer now.
你已經成為正式隊員了
Believe in your fellow officers.
相信你的隊友們吧
Right.
好
I'm off!
我走了
Wow...
好厲害
When did they learn to work together like that?
他們何時變得這麼合作無間了？
Report! Nakanoshima's unit has arrived!
報告，中之島小隊抵達現場
Sorry to keep you waiting, Ikaruga!
久等了，斑鳩
Ebina's unit has arrived as well and will assist in the southern quadrant!
海老名小隊也抵達現場，往南方進行支援
Thought you could get away with this, huh, you damn Kaiju?
你們這些為所欲為的臭怪獸
The senior officers who were off duty?
非值勤的前輩們
They came to help!
他們也來支援了
Shinomiya's team and Agatsuma's platoon have taken down two Yoju.
四之宮分隊和我妻小隊，打倒兩隻餘獸
This is Takao Platoon.
這裡是鷹尾小隊
Our gunners are ready to go.
狙擊部隊已準備就緒
We'll attack the Yoju in the air with freeze rounds.
我們將以凍結彈狙擊空中的餘獸
This is Itakura Platoon.
這裡是板倉小隊
We've secured the warehouse area.
我們已守住倉庫地區
We're starting to push them back,
我們開始一步步逼退怪獸了 明明就是隊長不在的緊急狀況啊
Okay, Minase, let's hurry and help the wounded.
好，水無瀨，我們快去保護傷者吧
Right!
好
Incredible...
好厲害
It's not just Kikoru and Ichikawa.
不只是琪歌露和雷諾
Everyone is incredible!
大家都好厲害
This is my division...
這就是我所在的部隊
This is...
這就是…
the Third Division!
第3部隊
You picked a fight with the wrong people.
你找錯打架的對象了呢
We're gonna win this fight.
這場戰鬥會是我們贏
Again...
又來了
It was the same with the attack you used to cut off my arm.
跟斬斷我手臂的時候一樣
You're slicing right through the tiny gaps in my exoskeleton.
精確地砍入甲殼之間的縫隙
This is no fun at all.
這樣一點都不好玩
Now that I know exactly what you're aiming for, it's easy for me to...
像你這種小花招，一旦知道你瞄準哪裡 我就能輕鬆地
handle it...
應付…
Hoshina-Style Sword-Slay Technique Number Two: Cross Slasher.
保科風格的刀伐術2式，交叉襲
Number Four: Wild Slasher.
刀伐術4式，亂襲！
So aiming for the gaps was just a diversion?
瞄準縫隙只是障眼法嗎？
Yeah, this is how a fight should be!
戰鬥果然就是要這樣才對
A head-on battle against an opponent whose strength rivals your own!
與勢均力敵的對手正面交鋒
Rivals! Rivals! Rivals! Rivals!
勢均力敵…
Huh?
奇怪？
Your core's a lot smaller than I thought.
沒想到你的核心這麼小啊
Number Six:
刀伐術6式
Eightfold Slasher.
八重襲
Got him!
太好了
That's the vice-captain for you!
不愧是副隊長
You see that, Kaiju?!
該死的怪獸，看見沒？
This is...
這是…
Not yet!
還沒結束！
Hibino-san? What's wrong?
日比野，你怎麼了？
Sorry, I'm fine.
沒什麼，我沒事
What's going on? My detection ability's going off when I haven't transformed!
怎麼回事？我明明沒變身 察覺能力卻發揮作用了
Vice-Captain...
副隊長…
It got bigger?!
牠變巨大了？
The position of its core shifted, so I wasn't able to fully destroy it?
因為核心位置移開了 我沒能完全破壞核心嗎？
Ultra-high temperature steam...
超高溫蒸氣…
Glad I brought it inside the training grounds.
幸好我把牠帶到了演習場
Its fortitude is rising alongside the heat...
怪獸規模隨著放熱而上升
No way!
這是…
Fortitude...
怪獸規模…
9.0!
9.0！